Guide to the Alfred and Hortense Wagenknecht and Helen and Carl Winter Family Papers TAM.583
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- II, Helen and Carl Winter Papers
  - II, Correspondence
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Abt, John, Sep 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Winter, Carl: Letter to Alameda County Educational Committee of CPUSA [Party Standards], Jun 1982 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Winter, Carl: Letter to Bennett, James [Director of Bureau of Prisons], Jul 15, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Crockett, George [Attorney], 1951 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Crockett, George, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Crockett, George, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Crockett, George, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Goodman, Ernest [Attorney], Jun 6, 1952, Dec 8, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Hall, Gus, 1980-1986 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Winter, Carl: Telegram From Isserman, Abraham, Jul 27, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with McPhaul, Arthur [Michigan Civil Rights Congress], Jul 28, 1951, Aug 8, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Parry, Will [Midwest Labor Institute], 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Winter, Carl: Telegrams from Saypol, Irving [United States Attorney], Jun 28, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Winter, Carl: Requests for Speaking Engagements and Information, 1958-1964 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Weissberg, Simon, 1950-Dec 1951 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Weissberg, Simon, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Weissberg, Simon, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Weissberg, Simon, 1954-Feb 1955 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with West, Jim [Party Leadership Standards], 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winston, Henry, 1983, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen and Michele Winter, Oct 1949-May 1951 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jul 1951-Aug 1951 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Sep 1951-Oct 1951 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Nov 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jan 1952-Feb 1952 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Mar 1952-Apr 1952 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, May 1952-Jun 1952 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jul 1952-Aug 1952 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Sep 1952-Oct 1952 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Nov 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jan 1953-Feb 1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Mar 1953-Apr 1953 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, May 1953-Jun 1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jul 1953-Aug 1953 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Sep 1953-Oct 1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Nov 1953-Dec 1953 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jan 1954-Feb 1954 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Mar 1954-Apr 1954 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, May 1954-Jun 1954 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jul 1954-Aug 1954 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Sep 1954-Oct 1954 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Nov 1954-Dec 1954 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jan 1955-Feb 1955 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen (Typed Out Transcripts of Letters), Aug 1952-Aug 1953 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jul 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jan 1952-Jun 1952 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jul 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jan 1953-Jun 1953 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jul 1953-Dec 1953 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jan 1954-Jun 1954 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jul 1954-Dec 1954 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jan 1955-Feb 1955, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Winter, Helen: Cards, circa 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence, Chronological, Circa 1949-1990s (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Abt, John, 1952, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Winter, Helen: Letter to Allison, Gene; Hortense Allison; Ruth Allison, Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Barsky, Edward [National Committee to Win Amnesty For The Smith Act Victims], 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Begun, Isidore [National Committee To Win Amnesty For The Smith Act Victims], Mar 2, 1953-Mar 3, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Charney, Hattie [Families Of The Smith Act Victims], 1952, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Davis, Nina, 1954, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Dennis, Peggy, 1952-1955 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Gallacher, William, 1952, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Goodman, Ernest [Attorney], Jul 18, 1953, Oct 19, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Winter, Helen: Letter to Goodman, William [Re: Death of Ernest Goodman], Apr 8, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Green, Abner [National Committee To Win Amnesty For The Smith Act Victims], Apr 1952-Feb 1953 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Green, Lillian [Chicago Committee To Win Amnesty For The Smith Act Victims], May 1952, Jun 1952 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, Oct 2, 1949-circa 1959 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Haessler, Carl, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with House Un-American Activities Committee [HUAC], Aug 1962 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Johnson, Oakley C., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Le Sueur, Meridel, 1952, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Mackie, Toini [Includes Book of Poems, "Rhymes Of My Times"], Feb 1954, circa 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Minneapolis Chapter Civil Rights Congress [Alma Foley; Includes Copy of Skit by Irene Paull on Arrest of Helen Winter], 1953, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with National Capital Area Civil Liberties Union/American Civil Liberties Union [Re: House Un-Americans Activities Committee Subpoena], Jul 1962 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Perry, Rose [Families of the Smith Act Victims], Jul 1952-Jun 1953 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Prison Authorities, Jul 1951-Dec 1954 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Ross, Ken [Co-Producer, "1913 Massacre" Documentary], Mar 2001-May 2001 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Winter, Helen: Letter to Rubin, Danny [Wills to CPUSA], May 23, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with United States Immigration and Naturalization Service [Gertrude Allison Machado], 1975 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Wayne State University Law School Repository [Donation of Transcripts of United States vs. Dennis], Dec 1993 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Weissberg, Simon, 1950-1955, Undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Williamson, Mae, 1952-1955 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Winter, Michele: Correspondence, 1950-1960 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - III, Political Activities
    Series documents the political activities of Carl and Helen Winter, and Hortense Allison, between the 1930s and 1990s, and is comprised of notes from meetings and conferences, drafts, articles, and speeches by Carl and Helen Winter; CPUSA memos, reports and ephemera; investigative files collected by the Detroit Police Department's "Red Squad" on Carl and Helen Winter between the mid-1940s and mid-1970s; teaching materials; memorabilia; and memorials for Detroit-area and CPUSA activists.
    Materials were generated and collected during Carl Winter's work as Chairman of the Michigan Communist Party in the 1940s and 1950s, as a journalist and editor of The Worker from the 1960s-1980s, as a founder of the Midwest Labor Institute for Social Studies in the 1980s, and through his participation on the CPUSA’s Political Bureau and Central Review Commission. Helen Winter's notes from conferences, convention materials, articles and speeches are primarily from her work as International Affairs Secretary of the CPUSA, member of the CPUSA's Political Bureau, founding member of the U.S. Peace Council, and proprietor of Global Books.
    Materials related to Carl and Helen Winter’s arrests and trials under the Smith Act can be found in the Smith Act Trials and Defense Work series.
    - "A Tribute To Ernest Goodman", Dec 13, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Action! Motown '97, Jun 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - AFL-CIO: Solidarity Day Certificate, Jan 18, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Allison, Hortense: Speeches and Writings, 1969, 1971, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, Metropolitan Detroit Branch: "A Tribute to George W. Crockett Jr.", Sep 1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Center For Marxist Education: Charles And Margaret Krumbein Scholarship Fund, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "Chain Letter To Ike", circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Cheprakov, V.: "Classes In Present Day Capitalist Society" (Translated From Communist No. 5, 1959), Apr 1960 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Chicago Committee To Defend The Bill Of Rights, Oct 2, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 1956-circa 1999 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Columbia College Chicago -- Paul Robeson 100th Birthday Committee: "Paul Robeson Rediscovered: An Annotated Listing Of His Chicago History, 1921-1958", 2000 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Communist Party of Columbia, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Communist Party of Michigan, Nov 1950 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Communist Party of Soviet Union, Jun 1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Communist Party of Venezuela, Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Communist Party of Washington State [Women's Committee Report], circa 1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - CPUSA -- 25th National Convention [1 of 4], Jul 1991-Oct 1991 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - CPUSA -- 25th National Convention [2 of 4], 1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - CPUSA -- 25th National Convention [3 of 4], 1991 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - CPUSA -- 25th National Convention [4 of 4], Dec 1991 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - CPUSA -- 27th National Convention [Keynote Address by Sam Webb and Other Documents], 2001 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - CPUSA: "Auto Industry and Political Economy" [Lesson Book], Jan 1957 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - CPUSA: "C.I. Resolution on Negro Problem in US" (TS, 10 pp), Undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - CPUSA: Draft Trade Union Program, circa 1986 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - CPUSA: Funds for the Future Campaign, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - CPUSA: Michigan Hall-Davis-Webb-Frankie Campaign '84 Report, Nov 1984 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - CPUSA: New Member Materials, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - CPUSA Constitution Committee, circa 1990, Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - CPUSA Control Commission: Communist Party Standards, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - CPUSA Lecture and Information Bureau: "Marxism and the World Today" Discussion Guide, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - CPUSA Political Bureau: "Political Bureau Resolution on Making a Turn in its Work", Jun 1981 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - CPUSA Second Extraordinary Conference, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - CPUSA Workers Circuit Schools: Notes for Teachers and Other Materials, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - CPUSA Young Workers Liberation League: "Why Nixon Must Go!", circa 1974 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Corvalan, Luis: Article in Nouvel Observateur (Transcription), circa 1977 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Crockett, George: Memorial and Obituaries For, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Dennis, Eugene: "On Uniting and Strengthening the Party and its Mass Work" (Draft Resolution to National Committee of CPUSA), circa 1958 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Detroit Urban League: Distinguished Warriors (Carl Winter), 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Detroit Police Department Red Squad: Copies of Index Cards Summarizing Surveillance of Carl Winter, Apr 1945-Jan 1972 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter: Biography and Photos, circa 1950-1959 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1945-1948, Undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1952-1956 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1965-1971 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - DPD Red Squad: Copies of Index Cards Summarizing Surveillance of Helen Winter, 1948-1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1948-1951 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - DPD Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1965-1974 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation: File on Michele Stone [Michele Winter], 1965-1966, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Ford Hunger March Memorial Committee: Receipt Book [Louis Leny], 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Global Books Forum: Invitation to a Latin Cabaret, Undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Goodman, Ernest: "A Dialogue Between Gordon, an American Lawyer, and Petrovich, a Soviet Lawyer, at Moscow - 1963" [Proof and Final MS], circa 1963 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Goodman, Ernest: "The Lion in Winter" [Profile in Detroit Free Press Magazine], Dec 8, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Hall, Gus: "Gus Hall Revisited," The Community Dispatch, Jul 1999 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Hall, Gus: Memorial Program, Obituary, Remembrance by Helen Winter, Oct 2000-Nov 2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Hall, Gus: Student Questions From Speaking Tour With Notes by Carl Winter, circa 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Hall, Gus: "The Communist Party USA - Changing, Growing, Swimming in the Mainstream" [Report to the National Committee of the CPUSA], Jan 17, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Hall, Gus and Henry Winston: Transcript of Soviet TV Interview With, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Hate Mail Sent to Carl and Helen Winter, 1961, Undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Helsinki World Youth Festival, July 28-Aug 6, 1962: Report On (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Jagan, Janet: Letter from Gus Hall, Clipping On, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Jewish People, Draft Resolution on Work Among [Includes Contributions by Jack Kling, Hy Lumer and Carl Winter], 1960 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - The Jewish Question: Clips and Ephemera [Soviet Anti-Semitism, Nazism], 1956-1962 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Johnson, Oakley C.: "Campus Battles for Freedom in the Thirties," The Centennial Review, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Le Sueur, Marian: Memorial Booklet For, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - "Life of the Party," City Pages [Profiles of Minnesota Communists Alma Foley, Meridel Le Sueur, Toini Mackie, and Helvi Savola], Oct 6, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Lumer, Hy [?]: Political Economy I Syllabus, Apr 1961 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Machado, Eduardo (Brother-in-law of Helen Winter): Clippings, Memorial, "Testamento Politico de Eduardo Machado" [In Spanish], 1960s-1996 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Machado, Gustavo (Brother of Eduardo Machado): Transcript of TV Interview with Machado on Communism in Venezuela, circa 1963 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Mahaffey, Maryann: Memorials, 2006, Undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Marxism-Leninism: An Introduction [Syllabus], Undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Memorials and Tributes [Detroit Community and CPUSA Activists], 1977-2007 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Meyers, George: Eulogy For, circa 1999 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Meyers, George: "Better Red," Profile in Baltimore Sun, May 29, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - "Michigan Militant" [Apparent Right Wing Group Calling for Death of Carl Winter and Other Michigan Radicals], 1964 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Michigan State Committee Communist Party: "Which Way to Peace" [Program Symposium on Events in Eastern Europe], circa 1959 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Michigan Worker: Request for Information, Dec 10, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Midwest Labor Institute for Social Studies: Announcements, Press Clip, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - National Labor Youth League Conference: Proceedings of the Final Convention and Statement by Michigan Labor Youth League, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - National Negro Labor Council: 40th Reunion Materials and "A History" by Mindy Thompson, circa 1956, 1978, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - "Peaceful Coexistence and the Ideological Struggle" (Editorial from Kommunist, no. 16), 1959 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Pollock, Sandy: Memorial Program, Remarks by Helen Winter and Letter to Sandy Pollock's Parents, Statement by CPUSA, Jan 1985-Feb 1985 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Progressive Youth Organizing Committee -- Detroit Conference, June 17-18 1961: Resolutions (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Reference Center for Marxist Studies: News, Fall 1992 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Russian Language Notes and Clippings, 1936, Undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Segal, Edith: "Peace and Jobs for Peace: Unemployed Americans Speak" [Poem], Undated (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Smith, Lasker: "A Story Book About My Life" [Self Published Memoir by Detroit Activist], circa 2000-2009 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Southern Conference Educational Fund: Memo Requesting Assistance for Rosa Parks in Detroit, Apr 17, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Tyner, Jarvis and Sam Webb: "James Jackson Jr. - An Appreciation", Sep 11, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - United Nations: International Year of Mobilization for Sanctions Against South Africa, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - U.S. Peace Council: A Detroit Tribute to Paul Robeson [With Transcript of Narration by Michele Stone Artt], Nov 14, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - U.S. Peace Council: Memorial Letter for Bernie Barth, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - U.S. Peace Council Michigan Chapter: Newsletter [Story by Helen Winter], 1984 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Wellman, Saul: Letter on Events in Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union, Apr 1990 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - "What is a Marxist Lenninist Home Library?", circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Whitty, Michael D.: "A Labor Revolutionary in Detroit" [Nat Ganley], 1976 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Winter, Carl: "A Guide to the Fight for Jobs or Income," Daily World, Apr 21, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Winter, Carl: Clippings About, circa 1940-1969 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Winter, Carl: "Club Education Outline on Struggle Against Unemployment and for Organization of the Unemployed", Jun 1982 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Winter, Carl: Daily World Q & A Column, 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Winter, Carl: Draft of Essay on History of National Movement of the Unemployed and National Hunger Marches, Undated (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Winter, Carl: "Great Decisions in Foreign Policy" (TS of Eight Essays), Spring 1963 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Winter, Carl: "Historical Materialism and Class Struggle": Notes, circa 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Winter, Carl: Letter to the Editor of the Detroit Free Press on McCarran Act and Kennedy Assassination, 1961, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Winter, Carl: Memo to Gus Hall with Comments on Hall's Report to Central Committee of CPUSA, Apr 19, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Winter, Carl [Michigan State Committee Communist Party]: Letter to Supporters on Campaign Against Mundt-Nixon Bill and Callahan Act, Jun 1948 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Winter, Carl [Michigan State Committee Communist Party]: "The Face of a Social Democrat: Walter Reuther" (TS), 1946 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Winter, Carl: "Memo on Petrov Outline of Contents for Proposed Book on History of CPUSA", circa 1970-1979 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Winter, Carl: Miscellaneous Notes and Fragments, 1981, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Winter, Carl: Nelson Mandela's Visit to Detroit: Guest Pass and Letter from Coleman Young, Jun 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Winter, Carl: Notes and Syllabus for Class on Dialectical Materialism [National Training School], Jul 1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Winter, Carl: Notes for Lecture on Unemployed Workers Movement of the 1930s, May 1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Winter, Carl: "Notes on a First Reading of Nemmy's Manuscript: 'Common Sense About Communism'" [Nemmy Sparks], Mar 1961 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Winter, Carl: Press Passes for Conventions and Rallies, 1958-1963, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Winter, Carl: "Production Forces and Production Relations in USA" [Notes and Reference Note Cards], circa 1934 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Winter, Carl: Readings on Communists and the Trade Unions, circa 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Winter, Carl: Report to CPUSA on Trade Union Movement with Related Notes and Clippings, Dec 3, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Winter, Carl: Report to Michigan State Committee on Meeting of National Committee of CPUSA, Jun 5, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 13)